export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. According to Joseph's interpretation to Pharaoh's dreams; the seven empty ears blighted by the east wind represented years of",
A: "famine",
B: "abundance",
C: "farming",
D: "Harvest",
answer: "A. famine",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Moses was born at a period when the Hebrews were",
A: "suffering",
B: "increasing",
C: "backsliding",
D: "rejoicing",
answer: "A. suffering",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. '...who is the Lord, that I should heed his voice and let Israel go?' After this statement, Pharoah",
A: "engaged Israel into forced labour with task masters",
B: "ordered midwives to kill all males born to Israelites",
C: "asked Israelites to fetch their own straws to produce bricks",
D: "decreed that Israelites' male babies be drowned in the Nile",
answer: "C. asked Israelites to fetch their own straws to produce bricks",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The name Moses means",
A: "baptized in water",
B: "abandoned in water",
C: "drawn out of water",
D: "thrown into water",
answer: "C. drawn out of water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. After the departure of the Israelites God made Pharoah pursue them in order to",
A: "force Israel to return to Egypt",
B: "hasten Israel's journey through the wilderness",
C: "make Israel obey Moses",
D: "get glory over Pharoah and his host",
answer: "D. get glory over Pharaoh and his host",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Who among the following kings was raised by God against the Israelites for going after the Canaanite gods?",
A: "Agap",
B: "Jabin",
C: "Zebah",
D: "Zalmunnal",
answer: "B. Jabin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Deborah a prophetess who was a judge in Israel was the wife of",
A: "Joshua",
B: "Abijah",
C: "Lappidoth",
D: "Sisera",
answer: "C. Lappidoth",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The sons of Eli were regarded as worthless men for all the following reasons except",
A: "sleeping with the women at the tent of the meeting",
B: "failing to attend the places of worship regularly",
C: "taking the meat for sacrifice before boiling",
D: "showing no respect to God",
answer: "B. failing to attend the places of worship regularly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Who was the first king of Israel",
A: "Kish",
B: "David",
C: "Solomon",
D: "Saul",
answer: "D. Saul",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Joel and Abijah were the sons of",
A: "Eli",
B: "Saul",
C: "Samuel",
D: "David",
answer: "C. Samuel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. '....Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice and to hearken than the fat of rams' This statement was Samuel's reaction to",
A: "David's defence of his sin",
B: "Saul's defense of disobedience",
C: "King Agag's defence of his victory",
D: "Eli's defense of the sins of his sons",
answer: "B. Saul's defense of disobedience",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. On Mount Gilboa, king Saul decided to commit suicide in order to avoid",
A: "ridicule from the Philistines",
B: "witnessing the death of his sons",
C: "being killed by his armour bearer",
D: "the agony of the injuries received",
answer: "A. ridicule from the Philistines",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. David bitterly mourned when Abner was slain by",
A: "Ishboshet",
B: "Absalom",
C: "Asahel",
D: "Joab",
answer: "D. Joab",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. One of the main features of Solomon's prayer at the dedication of the Temple was the",
A: "celebration of God who is faithful to his convenant",
B: "recognition that God loves sacrifices",
C: "assertion that God dwells in man-made houses",
D: "proclamation that no prayers be henceforth made outside the temple",
answer: "A. celebration of God who is faithful to his covenant",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In spite of Solomon's apostasy, his empire remained intact until his death because",
A: "God offered for David's sake, the punishment due to him",
B: "he won decisive victories over his enemies",
C: "he always took wise decisions",
D: "he made surrounding nations fight among themselves",
answer: "A. God offered for David's sake, the punishment due to him",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. 'Your father made our yoke heavy. Now therefore, lighten the hard service of your father' These were the words of",
A: "Jeroboam",
B: "Solomon",
C: "David",
D: "Ahijah",
answer: "A. Jeroboam",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Obadiah, Ahab's servant, made history for himself by",
A: "arresting the prophets of Yahweh",
B: "executing all the prophets",
C: "hiding and feeding some of the prophets in a cave",
D: "inciting the prophets to rebel against king Ahab",
answer: "C. hiding and feeding some of the prophets in a cave",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The contest between Elijah and the prophets of Baal took place at mount",
A: "Olive",
B: "Tabor",
C: "Sinai",
D: "Camel",
answer: "D. Carmel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. King Jehosaphat was commended for adopting his father's policies which included",
A: "removing Maacah, his grandmother from being queen",
B: "waging wars with the king of Israel",
C: "allowing the cult prostitutes to operate",
D: "burning of incense at the high places",
answer: "A. removing Maacah, his grandmother from being queen",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. God's constant love for unfaithful Israel is demonstrated in the book of",
A: "Amos",
B: "Isaiah",
C: "Hosea",
D: "Ezekiel",
answer: "C. Hosea",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. During the rebuilding of the Temple, Zerubbabel rejected the offer of help from the",
A: "inhabitants of Ammon",
B: "people of Samaria",
C: "friends of Sanballat and Tobiah",
D: "governors of the provinces beyond the rivers",
answer: "B. people of Samaria",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. 'And I asked them concerning the Jews that survived, who has escaped exile, and concerning Jerusalem...' These were the words of",
A: "Jeremiah",
B: "Nehemiah",
C: "Ezra",
D: "Hanani",
answer: "B. Nehemiah",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The presentation of Myrrh to Jesus signifies Jesus'",
A: "humility and servanthood",
B: "suffering and impending death",
C: "lordship on earth",
D: "kingship and messiahship",
answer: "B. suffering and impending death",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. 'My son, your sins are forgiven'. These were the words of Jesus to the",
A: "demoniac",
B: "paralytic",
C: "man born blind",
D: "centurion's servant",
answer: "B. paralytic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Peter called for the construction of three booths for Jesus, Moses and Elijah respectively during",
A: "the transfiguration",
B: "the Ascension",
C: "Jesus' arrest",
D: "the Passover feast",
answer: "A. the transfiguration",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The incidents that took place following Jesus' death on the cross did not include the",
A: "tearing into two of the Temple's veil",
B: "quaking of the earth that broke the rocks",
C: "the opening of the tombs",
D: "trembling of the chief priests",
answer: "D. trembling of the chief priests",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. 'How is it that you a Jew ask a drink of me...' This statement was made by the",
A: "Gentile woman",
B: "woman of Samaria",
C: "possessed woman",
D: "woman of Galilee",
answer: "B. woman of Samaria",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The Jews showed their hatred for Paul and Barnabas in Pisidia by",
A: "dragging out the apostles for stoning",
B: "insisting and driving them out of the Synagogue",
C: "influencing leading men in the city to drive them out",
D: "beating and stoning them in the Synagogue",
answer: "C. influencing leading men in the city to drive them out",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. When Jesus said'apart from me you can do nothing', he meant that Christians",
A: "pray without ceasing",
B: "must faithfully trust in him always",
C: "cannot pass examinations if they did not pray",
D: "should expect God to do everything for them",
answer: "B. must faithfully trust in him always",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. On the day of Ascension, Jesus promised his disciples",
A: "peace in the kingdom of God",
B: "amazing grace",
C: "power of the Holy Ghost",
D: "His abiding physical presence",
answer: "C. power of the Holy Ghost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. On Ascension day two men in white robes informed the disciples that Jesus would",
A: "send for them",
B: "be seen in heaven",
C: "prepare a place for them",
D: "come again",
answer: "D. come again",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. 'Go up and join this chariot'. This statement was made to",
A: "John",
B: "Paul",
C: "James",
D: "Phillip",
answer: "D. Philip",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Saul was converted on his journey to",
A: "Samaria",
B: "Jerusalem",
C: "Salamis",
D: "Damascus",
answer: "D. Damascus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following places was not visited by Paul during his first missionary journey?",
A: "Salamis",
B: "Athens",
C: "Antioch in Syria",
D: "Antioch in Pisidia",
answer: "B. Athens",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Paul was stoned and dragged out of the city by",
A: "The Lyconians and the Ephesians",
B: "enemies of the healed lame man",
C: "Jews from Antioch and Iconium",
D: "Jews in the Synagogue",
answer: "C. Jews from Antioch and Iconium",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The resurrection of Jesus is significant to Christians for it marked the",
A: "end of the Jewish faith",
B: "assurance of eternal life for Christians",
C: "beginning of Christianity",
D: "end of Jesus' earthly ministry",
answer: "B. assurance of eternal life for Christians",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. According to Paul, ' As sin reigned in death, grace also might reign through righteousness to",
A: "faith in God",
B: "the knowledge of God",
C: "eternal life",
D: "the glory of the father",
answer: "C. eternal life",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Paul in Romans declared 'for as by one man's disobedience many were made sinners, so by one man's obedience many will be made...'",
A: "innocent",
B: "righteous",
C: "faithful",
D: "Christians",
answer: "B. righteous",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is not true about spiritual gifts as taught by Paul?",
A: "Gifts should be used with all modesty",
B: "no gift can be independent of others",
C: "gifts have nothing to do with the level of one's faith",
D: "specific gifts perform specific functions",
answer: "C. gifts have nothing to do with the level of one's faith",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. In his comparison of the human body with the body of Christ, Paul did not mention the",
A: "hand",
B: "foot",
C: "eye",
D: "nose",
answer: "D. nose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The New Life in Christ operates through",
A: "humility",
B: "the name of Jesus",
C: "one body",
D: "wisdom",
answer: "C. one body",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. 'Death is swallowed up in victory, oh death where is your victory?' This statement is found in the book of",
A: "Corinthians",
B: "Romans",
C: "Galatians",
D: "Philemon",
answer: "A. Corinthians",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. According to Paul in Corinthians, the gospel message could only be lifeless when Christians",
A: "deny the resurrection message",
B: "persecute one another",
C: "gossip among themselves",
D: "entertain idolatrous practices",
answer: "A. deny the resurrection message",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Paul asked the Thessalonians to imitate his action of",
A: "demanding support from his converts",
B: "performing miracles",
C: "healing the sick",
D: "working for his personal upkeep",
answer: "D. working for his personal upkeep",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. With respect to the date of the Parousia, Paul advised Thessalonians to",
A: "be sober in maintaining their hope of salvation",
B: "disregard all speculations about it",
C: "know that the day would be announced later",
D: "enjoy peace and security in the face of danger",
answer: "A. be sober in maintaining their hope of salvation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Paul pleaded with Philemon to forgive",
A: "Barnabas",
B: "Timothy",
C: "Onesimus",
D: "Silas",
answer: "C. Onesimus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. James strongly condemned partiality in the Church for all the following reasons except that it",
A: "is contrary to Christ's example of humility",
B: "accords due respect to the rich who merit it",
C: "is a transgression of the commandment of God",
D: "does not harmonize with Christian virtue of love",
answer: "B. accords due respect to the rich who merit it",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The Galatians were reminded by Paul that they were Abraham's offspring and heirs according to",
A: "promise",
B: "good works",
C: "law",
D: "grace",
answer: "A. promise",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. According to Paul in Galatians, law ceased to be our custodian as soon as",
A: "it was made available to us",
B: "Christ adopted us as his children",
C: "we adopted the faith of Abraham",
D: "we stopped worshiping the elemental spirits",
answer: "C. we adopted the faith of Abraham",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. James advised Christians to portray their faith in Jesus by",
A: "listening to the word of God always",
B: "converting others to Christ",
C: "practicalizing their Christian belief",
D: "constant prayer and fasting",
answer: "C. practicalizing their Christian belief",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. On the fourth day of creation God created",
A: "the great sea monsters",
B: "the firmament",
C: "the two great lights",
D: "every flying bird",
answer: "C. the two great lights",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]